Diego Turtulici

Date of birth: 26 Feb 1993 | Nationality: Italian |

(+39) 3336554165 | <u>info@flowin.space</u> | <u>flowin.space</u> |

git.eigenlab.org/sbiego | Italy

About me: I am a freelance designer, web-developer, creative content creator and photographer while majoring in Digital Humanities. I'm interested in the creation and improvement of modern user-experiences and user-interfaces. My goal is to be a productive artist, trying to craft unique creations to improve experiences and express myself while learning various skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2008 - CURRENT - Italy

PHOTOGRAPHER - Freelance

Ex member of ASA25 Photographic Club (Vittoria) with some collective exhibitions: Vittoria Jazz Festival (2 times) and Fiera Emaia; A collective exhibition as result of a national contest by Imago Photography Club (Pisa).

Mainly as a hobby (natural photography, portraits, street photography) but from time to time some clients asked me to shot some photos while working on their brands.

2009 - CURRENT - Italy

GRAPHIC DESIGNER - Freelance

In the last years I created plenty of logos, posters, stickers, t-shirts, edited many photos and videos.

They were works for clients, friends, student associations, my personal projects and others.

2012 - CURRENT - Italy

WEB DEVELOPER - Freelance

I started building my personal website from scratch I endend up creating a custom bare CMS with themes. Later on any project I created or in which I took part had a custom website, for example: personal projects websites (notes sharing, UI experiments and themes), some custom fixes to CMS-generated websites and so on.

As of today I still prefer <u>using less libraries possible</u>.

2016 – Firenze, Italy

GRAPHIC DESIGNER – Kelevra (Band)

- Design and create band logo and identity
- Customizing a font

- Design and create band's first album cover and booklet
- Photo shooting and photo editing

2017 - Barcellona, Spain

GRAPHIC DESIGNER & WEB DEVELOPER – ElPoblet Cooperative

- Creating association's brand and identity
- Website design and creation (using Hugo static site generator)

2018 - 2020 - Navacchio, Italy

WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER – Libersoft / Imparaora / Tattooa

Libersoft / Imparaora

- Rennovating company brands and identities
- Design and creation of many documents (depliants, brochures, smartcards, banners, logos, templates, posters, etc.)
- Some custom static websites design and creation
- Website content editor and customization (WordPress CMS)

Tattooa

 Design and creation of documents (depliants, commercial banners, logos, posters, etc.)

2018 - Saonara, Italy

ILLUSTRATOR - Il Prato (publisher)

Cover drawing of the book "L'Ateo Virtuoso" by Daniele Scollo.

APR 2018 - MAY 2018 - Italy

GRAPHIC DESIGNER & WEB CONTENT MANAGER – FlyFish Sportswear

- Animation
- Commercial banners with photo-editing
- E-commerce design, creation and improvement (using Webnode CMS)

2018 - CURRENT - Bologna, Italy

WEB DEVELOPER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER – 1010: One Object One Owner

- Some websites design and creation
- Some interactive web prototype user-interface for a mobile app
- Creating company brand identity and graphics (logo, posters, business plan, depliants, brochure, business cards, etc.)

Other business to business works as: websites design, logos and many graphic elements for other companies like:

- Colnago Bikes
- Terzarossa Bikes
- Exept Bikes
- Elav Beers
- Gancia Wines

2018 – CURRENT – Vibonati, Italy

GRAPHIC DESIGNER & WEB DEVELOPER – IterTour

- Company identity rebranding (logos, documents, smartcards, tourist maps and panels, etc.)
- Design and creation of other elements (different logos, posters, etc.)

Personal project for IterTour:

- Front and back-end design, creation and management of an online menu for restaurants due to COVID-19 restrictions
- Front and back-end design, creation and management of a service for free beaches avaiability due to COVID-19 restrictions

13 JAN 2019 – 9 FEB 2019 – Bologna, Italy

WEB DEVELOPER - Dsign

Website front-end developer for some medical associations and a federation of associations.

DEC 2019 - Italy

GRAPHIC DESIGNER - Riccardo Palombo - Tech Is It

Creating identity brand with font logo and graphic material. https://riccardo.im/

JUL 2020 - AUG 2020 - Bolzano, Italy

GRAPHIC DESIGNER - Herberal / Comagri

Rennovating company brand and identity along with many graphic elements (brandbook guidelines, logos, busines cards, letterheads, document templates, etc.).

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2011 – Comiso, Italy

High School Diploma - Liceo Scientifico G. Carducci

2012 - 2014 - Pisa, Italy

Computer Science Student – University of Pisa

2015 - CURRENT - Pisa, Italy

Digital Humanities Student – University of Pisa

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **ITALIAN**

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production Spoken interaction		
ENGLISH	C1	B2	B2	C1	B2

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

4 JUN 2016 - Pisa

Digital Arts with Open Software (held)

An indipendently organized event at University.

9 NOV 2018 - University of Pisa

Basic Desktop Publishing (held)

During a student-organized University Festival.

19 NOV 2019 - University of Pisa

Graphics and Publishing with Free Software (held)

Organized by students' newspaper organization at University.

19 OCT 2019 - 21 OCT 2019 - Pisa

NASA Space Apps, international hackathon

LIFO Team - WasteCopter: web game, the player drives a drone into the ocean to identify waste from pictures (CAPTCHA-like, with a neural network)

https://2019.spaceappschallenge.org/locations/pisa-italy

DIGITAL SKILLS

Web

HTML5 | CSS3 | WordPress | Hugo (Static Websites) | Webnode | Bootstrap

Content design/creation

Desktop publishing | Image Manipulation (GIMP) | Vector graphics (Inkscape) | Digital illustration | OpenShot Video Editor | Krita Digital Painting | Game Design | Kdenlive | Darktable | Photography | Video and photo editing | Scribus

Office

LibreOffice | LaTeX | OpenOffice

Programming

Python | Git | Shell scripting | JavaScript | PHP (basic) | Python Flask | SQL (Basic) | Python Django | JQuery

Other

GNULinux | Open Source | Social networks

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Skills

- Attention to Detail
- Creative Thinking
- Effectiveness
- Identifying Problems
- Productivity
- Situational Assessment
- Task Resolution
- Problem Solving
- Teamwork Planning
- Decision Making
- Resourcefulness
- Self-Motivation
- Take Initiative
- Meeting Deadlines
- Meeting Goals
- Taking Charge
- Working with Others
- Review
- Diplomacy

COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Teamwork

- Helping others
- Conflict resolution
- Humor
- Collaboration
- Team-building
- Friendliness
- Providing Feedback
- Team Building
- Encouraging
- Mediating

Personal

- Active Listening
- Multitasking
- Persuasion
- Constructive criticism
- Public Speaking
- Caring
- Curiosity
- Focus
- Flexibility
- Verbal and non-verbal communication

CREATIVE WORKS

2016 – CURRENT

SenzaParole (SpeechLess) - Digital Illustrations

A collection of illustrations inspired by neologism and unique words. Words that speaks of and to our souls. Where imagination begins. Where words can't be enough.

Personal exhibitions

- 1. **Pisa** | 7 14 Apr 2016
- 2. **Pisa** | 19 25 May 2017
- 3. Museum of The Sea | Scoglitti's lighthouse, Vittoria | 11 13 Aug 2017

Collective exhibitions

- 1. Local market | **Pisa** | 26 May 2018
- 2. Local market | Livorno | 17 Jun 2018
- 3. Art in University Festival XI ed. | Pisa | 29 Jun 2018
- 4. Art in University Festival XII ed. | Pisa | 5 Jul 2019
- 5. Brilla Festival, Music Week | Milano | 23 29 Nov 2019

https://flowin.space/vision

Cloch - A Clock into a Hexagon

A prototype for a *graphical* clock built on a hexagon, which tries to experiment a new approach to time measuring. https://flowin.space/cloch

MinHex (game)

User interface and experience design and realization of an already existing readaptation of the classic Minesweeper videogame, built into a hexagonal lattice.

https://flowin.space/minhex/

JasterSind (game)

A JavaScript rewriting of the original MasterMind game with variable size. https://flowin.space/jastersind/

SOCIAL AND POLITICAL ACTIVITIES

Municipal Youth Council Representative

Municipality of Comiso

Between elementary and middle schools

High-School Student Representative - Consulta Provinciale degli Studenti di Ragusa

Province of Ragusa

Ideating and organizing the first local *OpenSource Day*, spreading the knowledge of FreeSofware in the province with some local associations.

2014 - 2015

Degree Course Student Representative

University of Pisa

Degree Course elected and Student Council candidate.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Summer School Camp – INPDAP (national insurance and assistance institute for public administration employees)

Locations: Malta, Plymouth (UK). Two weeks of english lessons with final exam, passed with merit.

5 FEB 2009

Special Award for Graphics – "Il dono" (the gift) cooperative

First classified with a studio photography designed and shot for the contest: "Oltre le frontiere" (beyond the borders), about discrimination-related issues, with caption by Gianluca Columbo. The category was expressly made for that picture.

APR 2009

Integrated Skills in English – Trinity College London

Entry Level Certificate in ESOL International (Entry 3), B1 of the CEFR Reading and Writinf skills - Merit Speaking and Listening skills - Merit

2011

Cambridge English: First (FCE) – Cambridge English Qualifications

B2 First, formerly known as Cambridge English: First (FCE).

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

OpenSource & FreeSoftware

Started both as a necessity and curiosity soon I became a linux passionate user embracing the FreeSoftware philosophy in any way possible, from work to everyday software.

I try promoting open software alternatives and almost anything I ever wrote is publicly distributed and it has an open licence.

Arts

I like experimenting with what I had trying to create something beautiful. Like I did with drawing, handmade jewelry, music player (some years in guitar school and other instruments basics are self-taught) and some experiences acting in the theater.

Technology & Innovation

I try to stay updated with latest technology both in consumer and prototypes both for personal interest and to be prepared to use them for work as tools or mediums.

Science & Phylosophy

With scientific and humanistic background I really enjoy divulgative themes science in theoretical physics, math, computer-science and their phylosophical implications as well as pure phylosophy. Would be one of my goals to work with real scientists and use my creative skills to make divulgative science or phylosophy more captivating.

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: **AM**Driving Licence: **A**Driving Licence: **B**